<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://georginaanna.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://georginaanna.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-05-31T16:43:38+00:00</updated><id>https://georginaanna.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Our Japan Itinerary</title><link href="https://georginaanna.github.io/blog/2024/japan-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our Japan Itinerary"/><published>2024-03-30T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-30T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://georginaanna.github.io/blog/2024/japan-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://georginaanna.github.io/blog/2024/japan-blog/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="osaka">Osaka</h2> <h3 id="arrival-day">Arrival Day</h3> <p>We flew with British Airways from London Heathrow and we had a beautiful view on entering the country of the famous Mt Fuji. Upon exiting the airport we headed to the Japan Rail Pass office and got our rail passes*, before heading to the travel card counter, where we got our welcome Suica, you must have one each and we put about 1000 yen on each. At the JPR counter they booked us on the Shinkasen and we headed to Osaka, you must reserve your spot as we thought this was really busy.</p> <p>Upon arrival we headed to our hotel which was called the <em>Osaka Guest House U-En, Osaka, Fukushima-ku Fukushima 2-9-23</em>. This place was a hostel but we had a private room and to be honest it was so clean (like everywhere in Japan) and we would defiantly reccomend if you are on a budget, we spent £150.00 for 5 nights - this is not a typo.</p> <h3 id="friday-15th-march">Friday 15th March</h3> <p>Head to Osaka Castle at half 8 leave Osaka Castle by half 10 Get to pommier restaurant (Lunch) 11:30 Denden town (30 mins - electronics) Head to Nara Deer Park (takes 51mins by 2:30pm Relax for abit then head to Dontonbouri (cheese coin, meat sticks, octopus balls)</p> <h2 id="kyoto">Kyoto</h2> <h3 id="day">Day</h3> <p>Saturday 16th</p> <p>head to Kyoto (store baggage at Kyoto station, 700 yen for big suitcase each per day - pay with suica card) (50mins from here to get to bamboo forest) Bamboo forest Tenryu-ji (temple) Togetsukyo Bridge Fu-fu-no-yu (Onsen) (The above 4 things are all an 18min walk from each other) Yasaka Shrine (@ night time) Gion District for some tea The Hotel Seiryu Kyoto Kiyomizu (roof top bar for drinks)</p> <p>Sunday 17th</p> <p>wake up and have breakfast in room - leave at 10am Fushimi Minato Park Fushimi Inari Taisa (large orange gates) Fushimi Inari Sando Chaya (food place) Bus to Kiyomizu-dera (3 stream temple) Bus to golden pavilion 46mins to get to gold pavilion Gold Pavilion - Kinkaku-ji Check into next place 5 minutes on foot from Omiya Station (Hankyu Kyoto Line) and Shijo-Omiya Station (Keifuku Arashiyama Line), check in 3pm Eat at Gyoza-dokoro Sukemasa Takatsuji Main Shop ぎょうざ処 高辻 亮昌 and relax</p> <p>Mon 18th</p> <p>check out late as possible (11am) Bus to Nishiki Market Micasadeco &amp; Cafe for fluffy pancakes Get Lunch in Kyoto and then head to Tokyo Food at curry place Drinks at bar Big echo Kareoke</p> <h2 id="tokyo">Tokyo</h2> <h3 id="day-1">Day</h3> <p>Tue 19th</p> <p>Gina uqilo/shopping Lunch out Mominoki House Ueno Shop, 4-chōme-5-2 Ueno, Taito City, Tokyo for drinks and massage/foot bath Taco restaurant</p> <p>Wed 20th</p> <p>Leave by 0730 get coffee/snacks on route (takes 1 hr to get there) Team lab planets 0930 Sensō-ji, 2 Chome-3-1 Asakusa, Taito City, Tokyo 111-0032, Japan Shibuya shamble crossing Nonbei Yokocho 渋谷のんべい横丁 for food Then 35mins to the The Jade Room + Garden Terrace to view the tower at night Shinjuku Golden Gai, 1 Chome-1-6 Kabukicho, Shinjuku City, Tokyo 160-0021, Japan</p> <p>Thur 21st</p> <p>Nakameguro 中目黒 (for breakfast) Shibuya sky and crossing in day Yoyogi park Meiji jingo Takeshita street</p> <p>Fri 22nd</p> <p>HATCOFFE Kappabashi Hondōri Shopping Street 合羽橋本通り商店街 Harmonica Yokocho (food stalls type place) Shimokitazawa 下北沢 Shinjuku Gyoen National Garden 新宿御苑</p> <p>Sat 23rd (big travel day) head to airport</p> <h2 id="japan-rail-passes-should-you-or-shouldnt-you">Japan Rail Passes: Should you or shouldnt you?</h2>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travelling"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="toc"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A plan for visiing three places in Japan]]></summary></entry></feed>